MAHMOUD HIJAZI

Sherman Oaks, CA 91411

Phone: 949.378.6274 | Email: hijaziii@hotmail.com LinkedIn: <u>bit.ly/3nsjsFs</u> | GitHub: github.com/hijaziii | Portfolio:

hijaziii.github.io/Personal--Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Management and Economics. Recently finished a 24-week intensive program at UCLA to upskill as a Full Stack Web Developer and engaged in a multitude of projects acquiring practical experience in the field. Known among my class to be determined to excel at learning and applying technology to practical business use-cases.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, (Java (In progress))

Frameworks: Node. js, Express.js, React.js, Redux, Sequelize, Bootstrap, Materialize,

Semantic UI

Databases & Tools: MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku, Git, OAuth, Postman

PROJECTS

Lunde Water | https://github.com/dmlunde/hydrohomies | lunde-water.herokuapp.com

Lunde Water (Continuation under DataSlate L.L.C.)

https://github.com/dmlunde/hydrohomies | lunde-water.herokuapp.com

KAMPers Visitors Management System | https://github.com/koyeary/KAMPers | kampers-vms.herokuapp.com

California Parking Services | github.com/hijaziii/California-Parking-Services | hijaziii.github.io/California-Parking-Services

EXPERIENCE

Junior Full Stack Developer DataSlate L.L.C.

01/2021 - 03/2021 Los Angeles,

California

I had the opportunity to upgrade the Lunde water project under DataSlate from pure Javascript to React (as a contractor).

- Research and Implement Frontend to Back- end interaction to Stripe API
- Build Backend API for
 - Customers
 - Questions,
 - Profile,
 - Orders/ Order Form

Full Stack Developer (Volunteer) **International American University**

07/2020 - 09/2020Los Angeles,

California

I started working with the American International University as a volunteer to continue to develop and progress my skills as a Full Stack Developer. I worked with a team of 3 to help develop a touchless visitor management system using the MERN stack.

Key Accomplishments:

The new system that I helped develop allows customers to custom schedule appointments either online or on-demand onsite using video conferencing. Customers with appointments receive customized QR codes upon approval via email which grants them access to the building. The system also integrates with Google oAuth services for ease of registration & access. Reminders delivered via SMS & email services.

EDUCATION

UCLA Coding BootCamp: Los Angeles, CA

03/2020 -

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

SUNY Empire State College: Saratoga Springs, NY

2003 - 2008 (Transitioned from American University of Science and Technology, Beirut, Lebanon)

Bachelor of Science - Business and Management Economics